Guide to the Cipe Pineles papers, 1925-2005 and undated RL.11739
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Cipe Pineles papers
1925-2005 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Pineles, Cipe, 1908-1991
RL.11739
18.0 Linear Feet
Cipe Pineles was an Austrian-born Jewish artist noted for innovations in magazine design, illustration and typography, based primarily in New York. Collection includes correspondence, photographs, drawings and illustrations and other design work, paintings, advertising and promotional materials, drafts of manuscripts, recipes, financial records and other printed materials that document Pineles's professional and private life, including correspondence and service orders during World War II. Collection also includes materials relating to a number of individuals: Ben Shahn, Carol Burton Fripp, Edward Sorel, Jay Leyda, John Alcorn, Mehemed Fehmy Agha, Sidney Meyers, Will Burtin and William Golden. Institutions represented in the collection include Alliance graphique internationale, American Institute of Graphic Arts, Art Directors Club, Harvard Graduate School of Design, Lincoln Center, Parsons School of Design and the Pratt Institute. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Files; Activities and Projects; Correspondence; Organizations; People; and Photographs.
Biographical / Historical
Cipe Pineles was an Austrian-born Jewish artist noted for innovations in magazine design, illustration and typography, based primarily in New York.
Born 1910 Austria; emigrate to US 1923. Bay Ridge High School, Brooklyn 1924-1926; Pratt Institute 1927-1930. Work: designer, Contempora 1931-1933; Assistant to Art Director, Conde Nast 1933-1936; Associate Art Director, Vogue 1936-1937; Art Director, Glamour 1938-1944; Art Director, Overseas Woman 1945-1946; Art Director, Seventeen 1947-1950; Art Director, Charm magazine 1950-1959; Art Director, Mademoiselle 1960-1961; Free lance designer, Will Burtin Inc. 1962-1972; Design Consultant, Lincoln Center 1965-1970; Director of Publication Design, Parsons School of Design 1970-1984; Visiting Committee, Harvard Graduate School of Design 1978-1981. First woman member of Art Directors Club 1948; Art Directors Club Hall of Fame 1975. Died 1991 New York.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Cipe Pineles papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2018.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Ben Rosen papers
Gene Federico papers
Leonard Sirowitz papers
Pat Finelli photographs
William Golden papers
Collection Overview
Collection includes correspondence, photographs, drawings and illustrations and other design work, paintings, advertising and promotional materials, drafts of manuscripts, recipes, financial records and other printed materials that document Pineles's professional and private life, including correspondence and service orders during World War II. Collection also includes materials relating to a number of individuals: Ben Shahn, Carol Burton Fripp, Edward Sorel, Jay Leyda, John Alcorn, Mehemed Fehmy Agha, Sidney Meyers, Will Burtin and William Golden. Institutions represented in the collection include Alliance graphique internationale, American Institute of Graphic Arts, Art Directors Club, Harvard Graduate School of Design, Lincoln Center, Parsons School of Design and the Pratt Institute. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Women artists; Jewish artists; Commercial art; Commercial artists; Women in the advertising industry -- New York (State); Jewish women -- United States.; Golden, William; Harvard University -- History -- Sources
- General Files, 1926-1991 and undated; 1
  - 40-50 Tenants Corporation, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - A Declaration of Peace, 1970 (Box 1)
  - A medal for Ben (Shahn), 1958 (Box 1)
  - A Project for Visual Education--Color Basics, undated (Box 1)
  - Ad Trend: Accentuate the Visual, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Address books, 1976-1978 (Box 12)
  - Advertising News and Notes, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Agenda for Louis G. Cowan, undated (Box 1)
  - Aristocracy of the Plucky, undated (Box 1)
  - Aspen International Design Conference programs, 1958-1966 (Box 1)
  - Association of Medical Illustrators, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Award--Society of Publication Designers, 1985 (Box 10)
  - Awards, 1934-1968 (Box 18)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes: Art Directors Club, AIGA, Type Directors Club
  - Awards, 1978-1985 and undated (Box 22)
    Includes: Art Directors Club, AIGA, Society of Publication Designers: Marie Archer Memorial Award of Excellence, Herb Lubulin Award for Continuing Excellence in Publication Design
  - Bay Ridge High School commencement, 1926 (Box 1)
  - Ben Shahn original lithograph purchase receipt, 1968 (Box 1)
  - "Bill" (from Showboat) lyrics, undated (Box 1)
  - Biltmore Country Market, undated (Box 10)
  - Biographical information, 1975-1978 (Box 1)
  - Book and history notecards, undated (Box 10)
  - Box with name cards lettered by Pineles, undated (Box 22)
  - Brownstone drawings, undated (Box 1)
  - Cat Fanciers Federation registration form, 1966 (Box 10)
  - CBS Television Notebooks, 1964, 1966; 2 folders (Box 13)
    1964 illustrated by John Alcorn; 1966 illustrated by Edward Sorel
  - Chart of the Golden family, undated (Box 1)
  - Check ledger, 1966 (Box 12)
  - Check ledger, 1985 (Box 18)
  - Chicopee Miracloth, 1958-1964 (Box 1)
  - Child Welfare League of America, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Cipe Pineles Golden cash receipts ledger, 1947-1959 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1926 (Box 10)
  - Clippings, 1952-1978 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1926-1975 (Box 20)
  - Colloquium on design, undated (Box 1)
  - Concert Artists Guild Award, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Cucumber painting, 1964 (Box 20)
    "For my darling dear Cipe to start her on painting again--xxxPdlyxxxx"
  - Day books (addresses, appointments, notes), 1937-1983 (Box 11)
  - Day books (addresses, appointments, notes), 1951-1987 (Box 12)
  - Department Advertising Design and Visual Communication Design Forum, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Designs and sketches, undated; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Designs and sketches, undated (Box 10)
  - Designs and sketches, undated (Box 19)
  - Designs and sketches, undated (Box 20)
  - Designs and sketches, 1957 and undated (Box 22)
    Includes: scrolled drawings; box top "Talon Ready Mix Foundation Promotion 1957"
  - Dictionary of American Portraits, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Do you have one of these 22 health problems? Here's reliable help!, undated (Box 1)
  - Editorial: Progress in Sarcoidosis (Louis Siltzbach), 1957 (Box 1)
  - Event invitations, 1962-1973 (Box 1)
  - Expired passports, 1977-1984 (Box 1)
  - Foreign book and magazine subscription prices, 1965 (Box 1)
  - friem's four pages (newsletter from A.I. Friedman Inc.), 1949 (Box 1)
    Includes article on Cipe.
  - Genes in Action mailing list, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Grolier Club agenda for Board meeting, 1960 (Box 1)
  - House and Garden Color Program 1946-1966 mailing (Box 19)
  - House moving, 1970-1982 (Box 1)
  - House moving, 1972-1982 (Box 10)
  - House renovation sketches, 1972 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Income tax, finance, 1972-1975 (Box 10)
  - International Design Conference, 1960-1962; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - International Editorial Design Forum report, 1982 (Box 1)
  - International Typeface Corporation "The Best of Newspaper Design", 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - Jerome Snyder memorial lectures on graphic arts, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Karl Fink & Associates, Package Designers Council symposium speech, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Knot design inspiration, 1967 (Box 1)
  - La Journee de Lindbergh, 1927? (Box 10)
  - Ladies Home Journal, 1964 (Box 18)
    Features article on herbs (p. 133f) illustrated by Pineles
  - Lease, 1946 (Box 10)
  - Letter to Congress on the Indo-Chinese war, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Letterhead and stationery samples, undated; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Library of the Performing Arts booklets, undated (Box 1)
  - Linweave Award to Pineles and Reba Sochis, undated (Box 1)
  - Mademoiselle from Armentiers, undated (Box 1)
  - Magazine illustrations, 1959-1965 (Box 19)
  - Material returned to Pineles, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Media News, Advertising Agency magazine, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Memo pads, undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Michael Friedsam Medal, Frank Stanton comments, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Museum of Early American Folk Arts brochure, undated (Box 1)
  - Music Center of Los Angeles County dedication, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Musical America, 1964 (Box 1)
  - National Society of Art Directors (NSAD)--Allen Hurlburt speech, 1965 (Box 1)
  - National Society of Art Directors (NSAD)--Award nominees, 1963 (Box 1)
  - New Clearing House of Art Information, undated (Box 10)
  - New Museum of Contemporary Art brochure, undated (Box 1)
  - New York Film Festival, 1969 (Box 1)
  - New York University commencement, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Non-Dissenters third exhibition, 1964 (Box 1)
    Non-dissenters refers to a term coined by art dealers such as Martin Reymert to denote 19th century European artists who were products of formal training outside the emerging strains of modernist theory in art. Often associated with the collecting habits of Muriel Butkin, who specialized in acquiring drawings from lesser known French artists of the 19th century.
  - Notebook, approximately 1926 (Box 13)
    Includes poems, song lyrics and stories in multiple hands; in English, Polish, German, possibly Hebrew or Yiddish
  - Notes and miscellaneous, 1955-1964 and undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Notes and miscellaneous, 1969-1981; 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Obituary, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Obituary--Funeral home receipt, 1991 (Box 10)
  - On the Rocks (Bernard Shaw) playbill from Mermaid Theater, 1975 (Box 10)
  - Opera News, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Package Designers Symposium--Pineles speech and other materials, 1964; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Painters of the Humble Truth exhibit, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Painting (landscape, trees), undated (Box 15)
  - Painting (possible self-portrait), undated (Box 16)
  - Painting (possible self-portrait), undated (Box 17)
  - Posters, 1969-1985 (Box 20)
    Includes: AIGA; Carl Laanes, MerryHappy; Harvard Computer Graphics Week; International Design Conference Aspen; Pratt; Rhode Island School of Design
  - Posters, 1964-1980 (Box 21)
    Includes: Lincoln Center; Parsons School of Design; two from Gertrude Snyder
  - Print Magazine (cover illustration by Pineles), 1985 (Box 10)
  - Printing News, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Pro.File: Cipe Pineles, Henry Wolf, by Gertrude Snyder, approximately 1980 (Box 19)
  - Projected bill for LG annual report mechanicals, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Promotional--Pineles biographical sketches, 1964-1978 (Box 1)
  - Publicity, 1964-1985 (Box 1)
  - Radio in Review--John Crosby, "I Remember, I Remember", 1949 (Box 1)
  - Redbook, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Regency Guide to New York: Promenade, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Renaissance Festival, undated (Box 1)
  - Right from the Horse's Mouth, undated (Box 1)
  - Robert Sivard review, Time Magazine, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Rockland Community College appointment, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Roslyn Rose typography, undated (Box 1)
  - Sakuragami (type of tissue paper), 1964 (Box 1)
  - Seventeen Magazine clipping with note, 1973 (Box 18)
  - Seventeen Magazine logo designs, undated (Box 1)
  - She's Been a Designing Woman All Her Life (Nancy Cacioppo profile of Pineles, Journal News), 1985 (Box 10)
  - Shizuko Yoshikawa "colour shadows", 1979 (Box 1)
  - Simpson Lee 3 new Teton colors brochure, undated (Box 1)
  - Sketch book "FC Personal", undated (Box 18)
  - Sketches and designs, undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Sketches and designs, undated; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Subscription requests, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Suggested Reading List (WNDT-13) program promotion, 1963 (Box 10)
  - The Art of Art for Children's Books promotional brochure, undated (Box 1)
  - The Place of Industrial Design in American Culture (August Heckscher), 1962 (Box 1)
  - Three Historic Palaces of the Tsars in and Around Leningrad, 1964 (Box 10)
    Outline and prospectus for a photograph and text collection
  - Trade Marks USA materials, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Trendsetters, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Type Directors Club, Suite Sixteen, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Typeface portfolio (Parsons Phototypographic Research Center), 1981 (Box 10)
  - Typography examples, undated (Box 19)
  - Typography examples, undated (Box 20)
  - Vanday Truex Endowment logo designs, undated (Box 1)
  - Vision Is My Dwelling Place (Jay Leyda tribute to Sidney Meyers), 1970 (Box 1)
  - Visual Environment of Advertising--presentation notes, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Vogue Food Diary 1978, 1977 (Box 13)
  - What Every Advertiser Should Know About Art Directors, 1961 (Box 1)
  - When the Work Is Done Next Fall (poem), undated (Box 1)
  - Who's Who In America--Cipe Pineles entry, 1962, 1965; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Who's Who in Graphic Art, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Why Business Should Support the Arts, undated (Box 1)
  - Why I Want a Wife (Judith Brady), undated (Box 10)
  - Window Into a Nest (Geraldine Lux Flanagan and Sean Morris, with note from author), 1975, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Women's Day Beauty Book, 1962 (Box 1)
- Activities and Projects, 1937-1986 and undated; 2
  - Bodoni Typeface, undated; 1
    - Font examples, undated; 9 folders (Box 1)
    - Vogue magazine body type, undated (Box 1)
  - Charm Magazine, 1956-1958 and undated; 2
    - Bodoni body type examples, undated (Box 1)
    - Christmas card designs, undated; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1958 (Box 1)
    - Miniatures, 1951-1954 (Box 13)
    - Stationery sample, undated (Box 1)
  - Cookbook Project and Food-related Materials, 1947-1977 and undated; 3
    - 1,000 Calorie Diet, undated (Box 1)
    - A Course in French Cooking, undated (Box 1)
    - A Cup of Tea, undated (Box 1)
    - Abridged personal guide to some good eating places in London, undated (Box 1)
    - Bancha, undated (Box 1)
    - Cookbook correspondence and miscellaneous, 1947-1964; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Cookbook layout and design, undated (Box 2)
    - Food and drink correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
    - Food-related clippings, 1963-1977 (Box 20)
    - Illustrations, undated (Box 19)
    - Mushroom recipe book, undated (Box 2)
    - Names of wine from tasting, undated (Box 2)
    - Recipe box, undated (Box 22)
    - Recipes and notes, 1969-1970; 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Vegetarian and food brochures, London, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
    - Why Michel Guerard Cut the Calories, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Hair Apparent, 1968-1971; 4
    - Clippings, 1971 (Box 18)
    - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Draft and planning, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Male hair book planning and design, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - Legal and Financial, 1961-1986 and undated; 5
    - Bills and related correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
    - Income tax correspondence and miscellaneous, 1965-1986; 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Legal correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - Martin E. Raphael correspondence, undated (Box 2)
    - Notes on finances, 1964-1968 (Box 2)
    - Polier and Tulin, 1961-1970; 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Robert Goldberg, accounting notes, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Sotheby's appraisals, undated (Box 2)
    - Will update, correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Travel, 1937-1975 and undated; 6
    - Bon voyages messages, undated (Box 2)
    - Cabin class passenger list, liner Europa, 1937 (Box 2)
    - Europe trips, 1967-1974; 5 folders (Box 2)
    - London trips, 1968-1974; 4 folders (Box 2)
    - London trips, 1972 (Box 10)
    - Radio Daily, 1949 (Box 10)
      Notice of Pineles and William Golden cruise aboard Queen Mary
    - RMS Queen Mary passenger list competition, undated (Box 2)
    - SS Europa telegrams, undated (Box 2)
    - Travel correspondence and miscellaneous, 1945-1975; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Vacation, 1965 (Box 2)
  - World War II-era, 1938-1957 and undated; 7
    - Attempted suicide condolences, 1945-1947 (Box 2)
    - Application for Federal Employment, 1945 (Box 2)
    - Cipe Pineles Golden clothing items to purchase, 1945 (Box 2)
    - Cipe Pineles Golden medical clearance, 1945 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1938-1944 (Box 2)
    - HQ U.S. Forces European Theater, Pineles orders, 1945 (Box 10)
    - Information Relative to the Employment of United States Citizens Recruited from the United States for Duty in the European Theatre of Operations, 1945 (Box 2)
    - Merrill's Marauders, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Notification of Personnel Action, 1945 (Box 2)
    - Overseas Woman magazine, 1945-1946; 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Pressed flowers, approximately 1945 (Box 2)
    - Standard contract for employment in the European Theatre of Operations, 1945 (Box 2)
    - TAGS magazine, 1943-1945; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Telegrams (William Golden homecoming from war), 1946 (Box 18)
    - Voucher for Per Diem, 1945 (Box 2)
    - War Department orders, 1945; 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Western Union telegrams, 1943-1957 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, 1925-1989 and undated; 3
  - Address lists, 1963-1977 (Box 2)
  - Arts Guild, 1929 (Box 2)
  - August Panorama, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Awards, 1963-1980; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Business and professional, 1971-1977; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Commercial, 1956-1966 (Box 2)
  - Cooper-Hewitt Museum of Design, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence lists, 1975-1980 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence written by Pineles, 1964-1976; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - David Webb Fine Jewels, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Department of Health, Education and Welfare, 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Envelopes separated from letters, 1935-1979; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Event invitations, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Family Service Association of America, 1963-1965 (Box 2)
  - Foreign, 1925-1980 (Box 2)
  - From Pineles' students, 1978-1981 (Box 2)
  - General, 1928-1977; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - George Brazilier (royalties on William Golden book), 1962-1965 (Box 2)
  - Holiday cards, 1949-1991; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Home improvement, 1968-1972 (Box 3)
  - International Design Conference, 1960-1963 (Box 3)
  - Kennedy Gallery, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Ladies Home Journal, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Mailing lists, 1960-1964 (Box 3)
  - Mary Mercer, 1975-1976 (Box 3)
  - Nine Pioneers in American Graphic Design, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
  - Personal, 1925-1989; 7 folders (Box 3)
  - Personal, 1961-1975 (Box 10)
  - Postcards, 1920s-1980s; 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Professional, 1947-1988; 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Recipe Christmas cards from the Goldens, undated (Box 3)
  - Telegrams, 1949 (Box 3)
  - Walker Art Center--Graphic Design in America, 1989 (Box 3)
- Organizations, 1947-1989 and undated; 4
  - Alliance Graphique Internationale (AGI), 1972-1983; 8
    - Bulletin 10: Montreal, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Conferences, 1972-1974 (Box 3)
    - Congresses, 1977-1980; 5 folders (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 3)
    - Student symposium at SUNY, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Will Burtin London promotional brochure, 1972 (Box 3)
  - American Institute of Graphic Arts (AIGA), 1950-1982; 9
    - Awards Committee, 1967 (Box 3)
    - Education Directory, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Educational Graphics, 1967 (Box 3)
    - Exhibition catalog, 1962 (Box 3)
    - Fifty Books of the Year, 1974-1975 (Box 3)
    - Magazine Show Certificate of Excellence, 1950 (Box 3)
    - Medal Committee, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Medalist Committee nominations, 1974-1978 (Box 3)
    - Newsletter and miscellaneous, 1962-1963 (Box 3)
    - Officers and Directors, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - Officers and Directors, 1961-1962 (Box 10)
    - Posters, undated (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Printing for Commerce Exhibition Certificate of Excellence, 1950 (Box 3)
  - Art Directors Club, 1947-1989; 10
    - Annual of Advertising and Editorial Art, 1949 (Box 3)
      Entries by William Golden and Will Burtin
    - Awards luncheon, 1947 (Box 3)
    - Certificate of Merit, 1961 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 1976-1981 (Box 3)
    - Event invitations, 1967-1989 (Box 3)
    - Hall of Fame, 1972-1977; 6 folders (Box 3)
    - List of winners, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
    - New York Board and member lists, 1961-1965 (Box 3)
    - New York publicity, 1948 (Box 3)
    - Newsletter, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Philadelphia exhibition, 1964 (Box 3)
    - Roster, 1975-1976 (Box 3)
  - Harvard University Graduate School of Design (GSD), 1960-1984 and undated; 11
    - Academic departments, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Calendar, 1980-1981; 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Clippings, 1979-1981 (Box 18)
    - Correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 3)
    - Dean's Annual Report 1982-1983 (Box 3)
    - Dean's remarks (Gerald McCue), 1980 (Box 3)
    - Democratic Theory and Urban Form, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Development Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 4)
    - Financial aid, 1981-1982 (Box 4)
    - Frances Loeb Library, 1981 (Box 4)
    - Gund Hall renovations, undated (Box 4)
    - Harvard and MIT courses, 1981 (Box 4)
    - Harvard Campaign correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 4)
    - Harvard Campaign Yard Line, 1980 (Box 4)
    - Harvard Committee to Visit the Graduate School of Design, 1980-1983; 5 folders (Box 4)
    - Harvard University and Radcliffe College, 1980 (Box 4)
    - HGSDNews newsletter, 1980-1983 (Box 18)
    - Interim report of the Overseers' Committee, 1982 (Box 4)
    - Laboratory for Computer Graphics and Spatial Analysis, 1981-1982 (Box 4)
    - Memorial Gifts to Harvard College, 1980 (Box 4)
    - Museums brochure, undated (Box 4)
    - News articles on the School of Architecture, 1979 (Box 4)
    - Opportunities for named gifts, 1980 (Box 4)
    - Posters, undated (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Pre-campaign report, 1979 (Box 4)
    - Publicity, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
    - Publishing Procedures course (Radcliffe), 1960-1961 (Box 4)
    - The Names of Harvard, 1980 (Box 4)
    - Visiting Committee, 1981-1983 (Box 4)
    - Where I Stand (Henry Cobb), 1980 (Box 4)
  - Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts, 1957-1968 and undated; 12
    - Associates of Lincoln Center pamphlet, undated (Box 4)
    - Book, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
    - Business expenses and notes, 1965-1966 (Box 4)
    - Calendar, 1965-1968; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Clippings, 1957-1968; 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1967; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Design consultant publicity, 1965 (Box 4)
    - Event materials, 1965-1966; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Fifth New York Film Festival, 1967 (Box 4)
    - Film Society of Lincoln Center, undated (Box 4)
    - Graphic design materials, 1968 and undated; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Lincoln Center Facts, undated (Box 4)
    - Lincoln Center Journal, 1968 (Box 4)
    - New York City Ballet, 1964 (Box 4)
    - New York City Opera, 1966 (Box 4)
    - Officers and Directors, undated (Box 4)
    - Opening of the new Metropolitan Opera House, undated (Box 4)
    - Philharmonic Hall magazine, 1964-1967 (Box 4)
    - Posters, 1965 (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Press release, 1967 (Box 4)
    - Proof A, 1964 (Box 4)
    - Publicity, 1967 (Box 4)
    - Second Season, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
    - Stationery designs, 1965-1966 (Box 4)
    - Teacher's Guide, 1965-1967; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - The Caucasian Chalk Circle, 1966 (Box 4)
    - The Country Wife, undated (Box 4)
    - The Little Foxes, 1967 (Box 4)
    - The Performing Arts, 1963 (Box 4)
    - This Is the Lincoln Center Fund, undated (Box 4)
    - Vivian Beaumont Theater, 1965; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Yerma: A Tragic Poem, 1966-1967 (Box 4)
  - Mademoiselle Magazine, 1960-1961; 13
    - Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 4)
    - Mademoiselle issue, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Parsons School of Design, 1963-1988 and undated; 14
    - Adam and Sophie Gambel Design Library, undated (Box 4)
    - Alumni calendar, undated (Box 4)
    - Annual Critics' Awards show, 1974 (Box 4)
    - BAC (Boston Architectural Center) continuing education courses, 1981 (Box 4)
    - Bank Street College of Education graduate summer program, 1978 (Box 4)